MATTHEW FORGET | AI/ML ENGINEER

Mississauga, ON, Canada • 647-745-4465 • matthewmforget@gmail.com Github • LinkedIn • My Website

SUMMARY

I am a computer science graduate with a strong interest in integrating AI into society. At York University I took courses in machine learning, pattern recognition, and artificial intelligence, covering topics like neural networks, VC dimensions, and PAC models. My experience includes developing LLM based mutation testing software using the OpenAI API and creating a heart failure predictor with machine learning algorithms

EDUCATION

York University- BA in Specialized Honours Computer Science (2020 - 2024) TensorFlow Developer certificate from DeepLearning.Al through Coursera

SKILLS

Java - Python - JavaScript - C++ - HTML/CSS - SQL - React Native - Flutter - ML (Sklearn, Pandas, Seaborn, TensorFlow) - Computer Vision - Neural Networks - NLP - Fine Tuning

RELEVANT COURSES TAKEN

Machine Learning / Pattern Recognition - Advanced Data Structures - Artificial Intelligence - Capstone Project (LLM Based Research) - Intro to Al and Logic Programming - Distributed Systems - Software Design - Design and Analysis of Algorithms - Advanced Object Oriented Programming

PROJECTS

LLM BASED MUTATION TESTER | VISIT GITHUB

- Conducted research and development on LLM based mutation testing using GPT 3.5 as the model
- Evaluated and analyzed mutation scores, compilable rate, and similarity rate of mutations generated by both Pitest and my LLM based mutation tester, comparing results
- Developed Python scripts to automate the LLM based mutation tester
- · Results indicated that GPT 3.5 turbo is not as effective at generating mutations as Pitest

PREDICTING HEART FAILURE IN PATIENTS | VISIT GITHUB

- Parsed data on medical patients (age, etc.) into training sections (80%) and test sections (20%)
- Used Jupyter Notebook to apply different machine learning models like logistic regression, KNN, and ensemble learning to predict the risk of heart failure in patients, with Seaborn to represent data, and AUC ROC to evaluate the models accuracy

CHESS APP | VISIT GITHUB

- Created a fully functional chess app using Flutter for cross platform performance, using dart
 programming language. A pure java version also exists on my GitHub that I made using android studio
 to test
- Currently adding Al functionality that will be a playable bot which learns to play like me

WORK EXPERIENCE

Warehouse Associate - Fraser Direct

Jun 2023 - Jan 2024

· Narrow aisle reach truck driver. Replenished Stock with a RF scanner

Container Unloader - ECM

May 2021 - Sep 2022

Unloading containers by hand, building and wrapping skids

Warehouse Associate - Hain Celestial

Sep 2019 - Dec 2020

Narrow aisle reach truck driver. Order picker using RF scanner